Okay, so here is our picture of our court counter app, or
حسنًا، إليك صورتنا لتطبيق عداد الملعب، أو
at least how we want it to look.
على الأقل كيف نريده أن يبدو.
Now, I'm going to follow my own advice and start with the XML first.
الآن سأتبع نصيحتي وأبدأ بـ XML أولًا.
Let's think about the view situation right now.
لنفكر في موقف العرض الآن.
So, we still have all these views, and these views are in vertical and
إذن ما زال لدينا هذه العروض وهذه العروض في الوضع الرأسي و
linear layouts.
المخططات الخطية.
We have a linear layout for team B and a linear layout for team A.
لدينا مخطط خطي للفريق B ومخطط خطي للفريق A.
and you can't just have two root views so furthermore,
ولا يمكن أن يكون لديك مجرد عرضين جذريين لذا إضافة لذلك
these are wrapped in a linear layout, which happens to be horizontal so
هذان متضمنان في مخطط خطي تصادف أن يكون أفقيًا، إذن
that these two child linear layouts can be next to one another.
هذان المخططان الخطيان الفرعيان يمكن أن يكونا تاليين لبعضهما.
Okay, now we want to add a reset button down here.
حسنًا، الآن يمكننا إضافة زر إعادة التعيين هنا بالأسفل.
For the sake of your brain not exploding thinking about all these
وكيلا يتعب عقلك من التفكير في كل هذه
different layouts, I want you to think of everything inside of this
المخططات المختلفة، أريدك أن تفكر في كل شيء داخل هذا
horizontal linear layout kind of like a single view.
المخطط الخطي الأفقي كنوع من العرض الفردي.
And now you're just trying to lay out this horizontal linear layout right here
والآن أنت فقط تجرب تخطيط هذا المخطط الخطي الأفقي هنا.
and this reset button.
وزر إعادة التعيين هذا.
You're trying to lay out two views.
تحاول تخطيط عرضين.
One view is at the top and the other view is at the bottom of the screen.
العرض الأول بالأعلى والآخر أسفل الشاشة.
So the question now is what view group would allow you to have
إذن السؤال الآن هو أي من مجموعات العرض ستسمح بأن يكون لك
a view up here at the top and a view down by the bottom of the screen?
عرض هنا بالأعلى وعرض أسفل الشاشة؟
And it turns out that a relative layout is a pretty good candidate for this.
ونجد أن المخطط النسبي هو مرشح جيد جدًا لذلك.
I can have my horizontal linear layout here, match the parent for
يمكنني استخدام المخطط الخطي الأفقي هنا، ومطابقة الأصل
the width, and then wrap content for the height.
للعرض، ثم تضمين المحتوى للارتفاع.
And I can have my reset button right here, align with the center and
ويمكنني استخدام زر إعادة التعيين هنا ومحاذاة المركز و
bottom of the pairing.
أسفل الإقران.
Okay, so you have a Relative Layout, and
حسنًا، إذن لديك المخطط النسبي و
that Relative Layout has a Button child and a Linear Layout child.
للمخطط النسبي فرع للزر وفرع مخطط خطي.
And the Button child is this Reset button, and
وفرع الزر هو زر إعادة التعيين و
the Linear Layout is the Linear Layout here, the horizontal one.
المخطط الخطي هو المخطط الخطي هنا، الأفقي.
Furthermore, this horizontal linear layout has two children, and
إضافة إلى ذلك، المخطط الخطي الأفقي هذا له فرعان، و
those children are also linear layouts.
هذان الفرعان هما أيضًا مخططان خطيان.
They are the linear layout for team A and the linear layout for
هما المخطط الخطي للفريق A والمخطط الخطي
team B that you see here.
للفريق B الذي تراه هنا.
The linear layout for team A has two text views and three buttons.
المخطط الخطي للفريق A له عرضا نص وثلاثة أزرار.
The same is true of this linear layout for team B.
المثل للمخطط الخطي للفريق B.
Five children, two text views, and three buttons.
5 أفرع، وعرضا نص، و3 أزرار.
This portion of the layout you've already made,
جزء المخطط هذا أنشأته بالفعل
you just need to add this, all right, let's do it.
فقط تحتاج لإضافة هذا حسنًا، لنجري ذلك.
Okay, I'm here in my XML code and so the first thing I'm going to do is is I'm
حسنًا، أنا هنا في كود XML ولذا فأول شيء سأفعله هو
going to make the Root Relative Layout that you saw in the diagram.
أنني سأنشئ مخططًا نسبيًا جذريًا الذي رأيته في الرسم التخطيطي.
So here going to type RelativeLayout, and I actually want
إذن هنا سأكتب RelativeLayout وأريد حقيقةً
to cut and paste these two lines because they need to be in the root layout.
إجراء القطع واللصق لهذين الخطين لأنهما يحتاجان لأن يكونا في مخطط الجذر.
So I'm cutting them and I'm pasting them here, in my root layout.
لذا سأقطعهما وألصقهما هنا في مخطط الجذر.
Okay, now I'm going to close off my RelativeLayout here and
حسنًا، الآن سأغلق RelativeLayout هنا و
I'm going to move this closing tag all the way to the bottom.
وسأنقل علامة تبويب الإغلاق هذه بالكامل للأسفل.
Okay, so what I essentially have right now Is this part of the diagram.
حسنًا، إذن ما لدي حقيقةً الآن هو هذا الجزء من الرسم التخطيطي.
All right, looks like I have some errors as well.
حسنًا يبدو أن لدي بعض الأخطاء كذلك.
Let's see, yes, I haven't defined a height or a width, so let's do that.
لنرى، أجل، لم أحدد الارتفاع والعرض، فلنجري ذلك.
Now my relative layout had the button at the bottom center of the screen.
الآن المخطط النسبي به الزر في مركز الشاشة السفلي.
So, to do that, it's probably going to need to fill the whole screen.
إذن لفعل ذلك، قد نحتاج لملء الشاشة بأكملها.
So I'm going to do match parents on both.
لذا سأنشئ أصول مطابقة للاثنين.
Okay, now I need to add the button.
حسنًا، الآن أحتاج لإضافة الزر.
I'm going to scroll down, right here, to where the linear layout closes,
سأمرر لأسفل، هنا، لمكان إغلاق المخطط الخطي
but I still am inside the relative layout, and I'm going to add a button.
لكنني ما زلت داخل المخطط النسبي، وسأضيف الزر.
And I'm going to go ahead and wrap content for that button,
وسأستمر في تضمين المحتوى للزر
because it's not a button that expands to fill the entire bottom of
لأن الزر لا يتسع لملء الجزء السفلي بالكامل
the screen or expands to fill the entire screen.
للشاشة أو يتسع لملء الشاشة بأكملها.
And now the parent of this button is the RelativeLayout, and
والآن أصل الزر هو RelativeLayout و
we're going to set the text of this button to Reset.
سنضبط النص لهذا الزر على Reset (إعادة تعيين).
Let's see what this looks like.
لنرى كيف يبدو.
Okay so my reset button's up here, that's not exactly where I want it to
حسنًا، إذن زر إعادة التعيين هنا بالأعلى، وهذا ليس بالضبط المكان الذي أريد أن يكون به
be, but it's parent is relatively out, that fills up the entire screen.
لكن أصله نسبيًا بالخارج يملء الشاشة بأكملها.
So I can align it to the parent.
فيمكنني محاذاته للأصل.
I want to align it to the parents bottom, and
أريد محاذاته لأسفل الأصل و
I want it to be in the center of the parent, horizontally anyways.
أريد أن أكون في مركز الأصل، أفقيًا على أي حال.
Cool, my button seems to be in the right place.
جيد، يبدو الزر في المكان الصحيح.
I'm going to select everything here.
سأحدد كل شيء هنا.
And I'm going to do a command option L on Mac.
وسأنشئ خيار أمر L على جهاز ماك.
Which is the same thing as Control-Alt-L on Windows to just reformat the code and
وهو ما يقابل Control-Alt-L على الويندوز لإعادة تنسيق الكود و
get it to look nice.
جعله يبدو جيدًا.
Okay let's go back to our Java code.
حسنًا، لنرجع إلى كود جافا.
Now I've got my button but it's not doing anything.
الآن لدي الزر لكنه لا يفعل شيئًا.
Let's start by making a method for it.
لنبدأ بإنشاء وظيفة له.
I'm going to make this right above the display methods, here, public void.
سأنشئ ذلك مباشرةً أعلى وظائف العرض، هنا، مكان فارغ عام.
I'm going to call this method resetScore,
سأسمي هذه الوظيفة resetScore (إعادة تعيين النقاط)
because that's what I intend for it to do.
لأنه ما أنوي أن تفعله.
Scroll up, I'm going to make it match these other methods
سأمرر لأعلى، وسأجعلها متوافقة مع الوظائف الأخرى
with the View v, and then, curly braces.
بالعرض v، ثم الأقواس المتعرجة.
I won't worry about what's going to go in here for now.
لا أقلق بشأن ما سيحدث هنا الآن.
I'm going to go back to my XML code And
سأرجع إلى كود XML و
I'm going to do the second part of the hooking the button to the Java code
وسأنشئ الجزء الثاني من ربط الزر بكود جافا
by adding a onClick attribute here for resetScore.
بإضافة خاصية onClick هنا لوظيفة resetScore.
Okay, so now when I click this button the code here will be run, but
حسنًا، الآن عندما أضغط على هذا الزر، سيعمل الكود هنا، لكن
there isn't any code here.
لا يوجد أي كود هنا.
Let's figure out what I need to add.
لنكتشف ما أحتاج لإضافته.
Okay, let's go back to this discussion of pseudoCode.
حسنًا، لنرجع إلى مناقشة التعليمات البرمجية المستعارة
When I hit the Reset button, what do I want to happen?
عندما أضغط على زر إعادة التعيين، ماذا أريد أن يحدث؟
Well, I want both of these two scores to show 0.
حسنًا، أريد أن تعرض كلا النقطتين 0.
Furthermore, I want the variables for score team A and for
بالإضافة إلى ذلك، أريد المتغيرات لنقاط الفريق A و
score team B to go back to zero.
نقاط الفريق B أن ترجع إلى 0.
Remember, when I click on any of these buttons, I'm adding two and
تذكر، عندما أضغط على أي من الزرين، أضيف اثنين و
then displaying the variable.
من ثم أعرض المتغير.
So, if I don't put the variable back to zero,
لذا لا أضع المتغير مرة أخرى على 0.
it's going to show an incorrect number.
سأعرض عددًا غير صحيح.
So here’s what I came up with pseudoCode-wise.
إذن هنا ما ظهر لي مع التعليمات البرمجية المستعارة.
The first thing I want to do is set the score for Team A to zero.
أول شيء أريد أجراءه هو ضبط النقاط للفريق A على 0.
Then I want to do the same thing for Team B.
ثم أريد فعل الشيء نفسه مع الفريق B.
Now both of the scores are zero, but nothing's been displayed yet, which is
الآن كلا النقطتين 0، لكن لم يُعرض شيء بعد، ولذلك
why in Step 3 I'll display the score for Team A, which has been set to zero.
ستعرض الخطوة 3 النقاط للفريق A، التي تم تضبطها على 0.
And to be a little bit more specific, I’m going to display the score for
ولنكون أكثر تحديدًا، سأعرض النقاط
Team A here, and then I'll display the score for Team B here.
للفريق A هنا، ثم أعرض النقاط للفريق B هنا.
And because in Steps 1 and 2, I've ensured that they're set to zero,
ولأنني في الخطوتين 1 و2 تأكد من ضبطهما على 0،
they will display zero here and here.
ستعرضا 0 هنا وهنا.
Then when I click any of these buttons to update ScoreForTeamA or
ثم عندما أضغط على أي من هذه الأزرار لتحديث ScoreForTeamA أو
ScoreForTeamB, it's going to be updating but starting with a score of zero.
ScoreForTeamB سيتم التحديث لكن بالبدء بالنقطة 0.
Okay, so in reset score I'm going to type my pseudo code as code, code.
حسنًا، إذن في إعادة تعيين النقاط سأكتب التعليمات البرمجية المستعارة ككود برمجة.
So the first thing I'm going to do is take score A and set it's value to
إذن أول شيء سأفعله هو أخذ نقاط A وضبط قيمتها على
zero using a assignment operator here and the value of zero.
صفر باستخدام معامل التعيين هنا والقيمة 0.
Oh and don't forget the semi colon of course.
ولا تنسى الفاصلة المنقوطة بالطبع.
I'll do the same for score B.
سأفعل الشيء نفسه لنقاط B.
After that, I'm going to display in the team A spot, the score for team A.
بعد ذلك، سأعرض في نقاط الفريق A، لنقاط الفريق A.
And then I'm going to display in the team B spot, the score for team B.
ثم سأعرض في نقاط الفريق B نقاط الفريق B.
I'll also go ahead here and add a comment.
أستمر أيضًا هنا وأضيف تعليقًا.
Okay, this all seems reasonable.
حسنًا، يبدو كل ذلك معقولًا.
And it's been a while since I've run anything on my phone, so
ومر وقت منذ قمت بتشغيل أي شيء على هاتفي، إذن
I'm going to press the Run button, okay, cool.
سأضغط على زر التشغيل، حسنًا، جيد.
I have a RESET button.
لدي زر إعادة التعيين.
Let's see if it works.
لنرى ما إذا كان سيعمل.
Good, it sets to zero.
جيد، إنه مضبوط على 0.
Let's click a little bit more,
لنقم بمزيد من الضغط
just to make sure that everything's still working.
فقط لنتأكد من أن كل شيء ما زال يعمل.
Cool, and it looks like it is, awesome.
جيد، يبدو كذلك، مدهش.
Now this was a little bit of a tricky one.
الآن هذا كان صعبًا بعض الشيء.
So let me show you what happens if you were to switch around the order,
إذن دعني أريك ما يحدث إذا قمت بتبديل الترتيب
do something a little bit differently.
وفعلت شيئًا مختلفًا قليلًا.
What if I switch these two around?
ماذا إذا أبدلت هذين؟
Well, let's just see what happens.
حسنًا، لنرى ما سيحدث.
Okay, so here it is, let's see what it does.
حسنًا، إذن ها هو، لنرى ما كان.
Okay, so I'm going to add some points.
حسنًا، إذن سأضيف بعض النقاط.
Now for the moment of truth, Reset button.
الآن، بالفعل، زر إعادة التعيين.
Huh, doesn't seem to do anything.
لا يبدو أنه يفعل أي شيء.
Let's try clicking, huh, interesting.
لنجرب النقر، مدهش.
Well it's kind of hard to see,
حسنًا من الصعب رؤيته،
but the score before said 19, I hit the reset button nothing changed.
لكن النقاط كانت تقول 19، ضغطت على زر إعادة التعيين ولم يتغير شيء.
But then when I hit free throw it showed one.
لكن عندما ضغطت على الرمية الحرة ظهر العدد واحد.
let's try with the other side, if I hit plus two points.
لنجرب الجانب الآخر، إذا ضغطت على إضافة نقطتين.
Oh, it shows two.
يظهر العدد 2.
let's look at the code again for why that might be the case.
لنرى الكود مرة أخرى لمعرفة سبب هذه الحالة.
So I switched around displaying and setting the score.
إذن أبدلت العرض وإعداد النقاط.
Just to see what kind of error behavior I might get from that.
لمعرفة نوع سلوك الخطأ الذي قد أحصل عليه من هذا.
Let's say TeamA has a score of 30 and TeamB has a score of 40.
لنقل أن نقاط TeamA هي 30 وأن نقاط TeamB هي 40.
When I say displayForTeamA it's going to show 30 and
عندما أقول displayForTeamA ستعرض 30 و
when I say displayForTeamB it's going to show 40.
عندما أقول displayForTeamB ستعرض 40.
Only after that, will it actually set these values to zero.
فقط بعد ذلك، تتعين هاتان القيمتان على 0.
But since it displayed first it's not going to show the values of zero.
لكن لأنه تم عرضها أولًا فلن تظهر القيمتين 0.
But the variable will be zero.
لكن المتغير سيكون 0.
So when I press something like addThreeForTeamB, it's going to take
إذن عندما أضغط على شيء مثل addThreeForTeamB ستأخذ
the value of zero that I set down here, add three, and then display three.
القيمة 0 التي ضبطها بالأسفل هنا وتضيف 3 ثم تعرض 3.
So to us, it would look like TeamB went from having a score of 30 then to
إذن بالنسبة لنا، سيبدو أن TeamB كان لها 30 نقطة ثم
after clicking the reset button, a score of three, which is kind of a weird jump.
بعد النقر على زر إعادة التعيين، أصبحت النقاط 3، وهو انتقال غريب.
Now one way I could fix this besides swapping it back to how it should be
الآن طريقة أخرى لإصلاح ذلك بجانب الرجوع إلى ما كان يجب أن تكون عليه
Is I could put display zero here.
هي أنه يمكنني وضع عرض 0 هنا.
And you can test this out on your own, but this would actually work.
يمكنك اختبار ذلك بنفسك لكنه يعمل بالفعل.
It's just a little bit counterintuitive.
إنه فقط غير منطقي قليلًا.
I like showing examples like this because it kind of shows the beauty and
أحب عرض أمثلة كهذه لأنها تظهر جمال
subjectivity of code.
ذاتية الكود.
Now, in this case, I happen to think fairly strongly that the first way that
الآن، في هذه الحالة، أميل بشدة للتفكير في أن الطريقة الأولى
I had the code was better.
التي كان لدي فيها الكود كانت أفضل.
But you might start seeing scenarios where there could be two different
لكن قد تلاحظ مواقف فيها طريقتان
ways to write the code, and both of them are technically correct.
مختلفتان لكتابة الكود، وكل منهما صحيحة من الناحية التقنية.
Since there isn't always one right answer,
ولأنه لا توجد دائمًا إجابة صحيحة واحدة،
you shouldn't feel constricted to do it the exact correct way.
لا يجب الالتزام بفعل الأمر بالطريقة الصحيحة بالضبط.
Try coding up something that works your way, see how other people do it,
جرب برمجة شيء يعمل بطريقتك، وشاهد كيف يفعله الآخرون
and then compare, who's more efficient, whose code is clearer.
ثم قارن، أي طريقة كانت أكثر كفاءة، وأي الأكواد كان أوضح.
These kind of discussions could be a really helpful learning experience.
هذا النوع من النقاشات يمكنه تشكيل تجربة تعلم مفيدة بالفعل.
Okay, but I'm going to revert the code back to the state that it was before
حسنًا، لكنني سأعكس الكود للحالة التي كان عليها من قبل
which was working and
والتي كان يعمل فيها و
now I have all the functionality of my app but it's not pretty, let's fix that.
الآن لدي كل عمل تطبيقي، لكنه ليس جيدًا، لنصلح هذا.